

### Soheil Novinfard

Mobile Software Engineer (iOS Developer)

# Personal Information

Location: United Kingdom, London

Place of Birth: Iran, Tehran Date of Birth: 1990/September/10

# Contact Information

Phone: +44-7377178277 Email: novinfard@gmail.com

Website: www.novinfard.com GitHub: www.github.com/novinfard

# **Profile**

I am independent iOS developer with 5 year full-stack development background, working on some freelance and personal projects. Before coming to London, I worked at Ima Ravesh company (NiniPlus) as iOS developer for last 3 years. We created a new app for the community of pregnant women where I built its iOS application, the real-time architecture of the software, associated web application backends, monitoring services and the RESTful and socket-based API.

Nationality: Iran

# Academic Background

#### QUEEN MARY UNIVERSITY OF LONDON - 2017-2019

Master's degree, Software Engineering with Industrial Experience

## **SHARIF UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY – 2013-2015**

Master's degree, Computer Systems Networking and Telecommunications

#### Main Skills

Mobile Applications, Objective-C, Swift, Backend Development, Web-socket, RESTful WebServices, CoreData, Realm

#### Other Skills

Project Management, Real-time applications, Web Applications, PHP, MySQL, MongoDB, Codelgniter, Joomla!, XHTML, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Scrum, Source Control, Git

#### **Publications**

M.R.Shahmoradi, S.Novinfard, "Developing a web service to automatic mapping web pages to mobile devices" 15th Iranian students conference on electrical engineering (ISCEE2012), August 2012

### Academic Awards

Organiser at 17th Iranian students conference on electrical engineering (ISCEE2014), December 2014

Best Panel Chairman at 16th Iranian students conference on electrical engineering (ISCEE2013), September 2013

## Certificates

#### Web Developing Engineer with JavaScript

Technical and Vocational education organiser of IRAN MARCH 2010, GRADE 74 FROM 100, 304 HOURS

# **Work Experience**

#### Self-Employed iOS Developer; London, United Kingdom

JANUARY 2016 - PRESENT

**Smart Wallet iOS Application** January 2018 - present

This application assists for managing money. Different reports are presented in the application to help the user managing their money and budget. (written in Swift)

**Transcription Helper iOS application** September 2016 - present

The Transcribe Helper application is an assistant for people who want to work out a piece of audio, in order to write it out. (written in Objective-C)

#### iOS Developer at Ima Ravesh; Tehran, Iran

AUGUST 2014 - AUGUST 2017

Niniplus mobile application March 2014 - August 2017

Social network and real-time messaging for the community of pregnant women

Niniplus SMS web application August 2014 - March 2014

This application is an interactive SMS system which provides weekly messaging for pregnant women

#### Founder & Lead Web Application Developer at Egolt; Tehran, Iran

MARCH 2012 - JUNE 2017

Egolt Archive / Project / Voting / Like / Tooltip Joomla! extensions April 2013 - June 2017

#### Web Application Developer at Islamic Republic of Iran Broadcasting; Tehran, Iran

FEBRUARY 2009 - MARCH 2013

Negah Media web applicationSeptember 2009 - January 2011Kerman / Semnan / Hamadan IRIB websiteSeptember 2011 - May 2012

# Languages

**ENGLISH** PROFESSIONAL WORKING PROFICIENCY

IELTS Academic Module Certificate with band score 7.0 (20th April 2017)

PERSIAN NATIVE

# Interests and hobbies

Watching movies, Playing piano, Reading tech articles, Fitness